Neugass, Fritz; Papers ger007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Art and Artists, 1950s-1979; 1; 260 file folders
  - Illumination, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescript, photographs (9), clippings.
  - Images of Man. Exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
  - Impressionisten: Impressionists. Exhibits at Knoedler, 1966 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    and at the Metropolitan Museum, 1975. Typescripts (3), photographs (18), clippings.
  - Industry as patron of the arts, including Chase Bank, Manhattan, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (29), clippings.
  - Ingres, Jean-Auguste-Dominique. Exhibit at Fogg Museum, 1967 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
    Typescript, photographs (10), clippings.
  - Irish Art. Exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1977 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
    With illustrated catalog. Typescript, notes, photographs (24), publicity, clippings.
  - Islamic Art. Exhibits at Metropolitan Museum, including from the Houghton Shah-nameh, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (36), publicity, clippings.
  - Italian Drawings. Exhibit Metropolitan Museum, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescript, photographs (47), publicity.
  - Italian Frescoes. Exhibit Metropolitan Museum, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Typescript, photographs (37), clippings.
  - Japanische Kunst: Japanese Art, also modern art scene in Japan, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (35), clippings.
  - Jawlensky, Alexey. Including catalog of Hutton Gallery, 1965 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Typescript, publicity, clippings.
  - Jemen: Yemen, Excavations by Wendell Phillips, "In the footsteps of the Queen Sheba", Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
    Typescript, photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - Johns, Jasper. Exhibit at the Whitney Museum, 1977 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    Typescript, photographs (29), publicity, clippings.
  - Kandinsky, Vasily. Exhibits, Sotheby auction catalogue, London, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    Sale of 50 Kandinskys from Guggenheim Museum. Typescripts (3), photographs (21), clippings.
  - Kirchner, Ernst Ludwig. Traveling exhibit in the U.S. 1969, with illustrated catalog, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Photographs (19), publicity, clippings.
  - Klapheck, Konrad. Exhibit at Sidney Janis, 1969 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    With catalog. Typescript, clippings.
  - Klee, Paul. Notes, but no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
  - Knaus, Robert. Exhibit New York, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    With illustrated catalog. Typescript, clipping.
  - Kokoschka, Oskar, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (4), clippings.
  - Kollwitz, Käthe. Review of Kathe Kollwitz Drawings, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
  - Kooning, Willem de, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (26), publicity, clippings.
  - Krause, Karl-Heinz, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 30)
    Typescript, illustrated catalogs, publicity, clippings. Original artwork, signed, dated (stored in vault, 6-2-4).
  - Kunst Standard: Art Bolshevism, material on the reaction against modern art, Dondero, Huntington Hartford, etc., Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 31)
    Typescript notes, clippings.
  - Kunst: Diebstahle, art thefts, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 32)
    Typescripts (11), photographs (12).
  - Kunst: Diebstahle, art thefts, Undated (Box 4 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 33)
    Clippings, etc.
  - Kunstraub: Art Robbery, Smuggling, Mexico, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
  - Kunst-Saison: Art Season in New York, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Various articles on exhibits and other notices on art in New York in the 1950s and 1960s.
  - Kupka, Frantisek. Exhibit at the Guggenheim Museum, 1975 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    With corrected proof sheets of catalog, no text by Fritz Neugass. Publicity, clippings.
  - Land-Art: Earth art, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    Typescript, photographs (2), clippings.
  - Latein-Amerika Malerei: Latin-American painting, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    Typescript, photographs (19), publicity, clipping.
  - La Tour, Georges de. Purchase of "The Fortune Teller" by Metropolitan Museum, 1960 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
  - Léger, Fernand, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
  - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Leonardo da Vinci, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Articles, including purchase of doubtful works by Detroit and the Metropolitan Museum, various versions of the "Mona Lisa", etc.
    Typescripts (13), photographs (10), publicity, clippings.
  - LeWitt, Sol. Exhibit at Museum of Modern Art, 1978 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (5), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Lichtenstein, Roy, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    Typescript, photographs (15), publicity, clippings.
  - Lindner, Richard. No text by Neugass, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Photographs (2), publicity, catalogs, clippings.
  - Lingelbach, Johannes, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
    Purchase of Rome scene by Worcester Museum, including Museum Bulletin with essay on the artist, pencil draft by Fritz Neugass, no finished text, photograph.
  - Madonnen Bilder: Madonnas. Exhibits in the Metropolitan Museum, Undated; typescript (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
  - Manet, Edouard, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    Typescript, drafts, photographs (21), publicity, clippings.
  - Manet, Edouard. "Olympia", Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (3), clippings.
  - Maschine in der Kunst: Machines in art, exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1968-1969 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
  - Master E.S. 500 year jubilee exhibit, Philadelphia, 1967 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
  - Matisse, Henri, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (40).
  - Matisse, Henri, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
    Catalogs, publicity, clippings.
  - Medici family. "Twilight of the Medici", Florentine late baroque exhibit in Detroit, 1974 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
  - Merode Altar of the Master of Flémalle, purchase by the Metropolitan Museum, 1957 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (7), clippings.
  - Merveldt, Hanns Hubertus Graf von, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Includes original signed graphic work by the artist (stored in vault), typescripts (2), biographical materials.
  - Michelangelo. Drawings, statue of St. John, possible work of his youth, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Typescripts (3), notes, photographs (9), clippings.
  - Michelangelo. Exhibit "Michelangelo and His World" at the Morgan Library, 1979 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (10), publicity.
  - Miró, Joan, 1959 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    Typed notes, autograph of the artist with his address, which he gave Fritz Neugass during the Miró exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art.
    Photographs (10), clippings.
  - Modern Art in Your Life. Exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1949 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
  - Modigliani, Amedeo, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
  - Mondrian, Piet, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
  - Monet, Claude. Exhibit at Museum of Modern Art, 1960 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 30)
    See also Box 25, Folder 9.
    Typescript, photographs (20), publicity, clippings.
  - Montreal exposition, 1967 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 31)
    Typescript, photographs (20), list of art displayed, clippings.
  - Morgan, Barbara. Original photo, publicity, catalogs, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 32)
  - Morgantina. Excavations in Sicily by Princeton University, 1958 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 33)
    Typescript, photographs (23), reprints, clippings.
  - Morisot, Berthe, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 34)
    Typescript, photographs (6), catalogs.
  - Moses, Grandma (Anna Mary Robertson Moses), Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 35)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (29), publicity, clippings.
  - Münter, Gabriele, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 36)
    Typescript, illustrated catalog, publicity, clippings.
  - Mullen, Buell, Undated (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 37)
    Typescript, notes, original photos by Fritz Neugass, photographs (19), clippings.
  - Munch, Edvard. Exhibit in Washington, 1979 (Box 5 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 38)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (15), publicity, clippings.
  - Nadelman, Elie, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Typescript, photographs (5), clippings.
  - Neo-Classicism. Exhibit in Cleveland, 1964 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    No finished text by Neugass. Photographs (5), publicity.
  - Neo-Impressionism, Exhibit at the Guggenheim Museum, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Typescript, photographs (13), clippings.
  - Nevelson, Louise, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
  - New York School, 1940-1970 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
    Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1970, no text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (23), clippings.
  - Nike von Samothrake: Nike of Samothrace. New excavations, ca. 1949 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (7), publicity, clipping.
  - Noguchi, Isamu, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
  - Nolde, Emil, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescript, photographs (10), color reproductions, publicity, clippings.
  - O'Keefe, Georgia, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (14), publicity, clippings.
  - Op Art. "The Responsive Eye", exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1965 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (15), publicity, clippings.
  - Persepolis. Excavations in Persia by the University of Chicago, 1953 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
    Typescript, correspondence, publicity, book plates.
  - Das Phantastische in der Kunst: The Fantastic in Art. Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1952 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Typescript, photographs (33), publicity, clippings.
  - Picard, Lil. Catalogs, clippings, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
  - Picasso, Pablo, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
    Typescripts (6), photographs (55), publicity.
    See also Box 25, Folder 10.
  - Picasso, Pablo, Undated; clippings (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
  - Picasso, Pablo, Undated; clippings (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
  - Polish Artists, modern artists in Poland. Exhibits, 1961, 1963 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
  - Pollock, Jackson Pollack, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Typescripts (8), photographs (25), publicity.
  - Pompeii AD 79. Traveling exhibit in US, 1978-1979 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Typescript, photographs (7), publicity, clippings.
  - Pop Art. Exhibits, 1963 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
    Typescript, photographs (19), publicity.
  - Pop Art, Undated; clippings (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
  - Prae-Kolumbische Kunst: Pre-Columbian Art, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (45).
  - Prae-Kolumbische Kunst: Pre-Columbian Art. "Before Cortés" exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1970 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Photographs (20), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Primitive Art. "Art of Oceania, Africa, and the Americas", exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (21), publicity.
  - Primitive Art. "Mastercraftsmen of Peru", Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, 1968 (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
  - Primitive Art. Mexican art of the Kurt Stavenhagen Collection, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
  - Primitive Art. Michael Rockefeller researches in New Guinea, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    Typescript, photographs (27), catalog, publicity, clippings.
  - Primitive Art. Portraits of colonial officers, exhibit in Chicago, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
    Photographs (10), publicity, clippings.
  - Primitive Art. West Indian folk art in New Mexico, Santos, Undated (Box 6 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
  - Raphael. Portrait "A young woman", purchased by Boston Museum in 1970, and return to Italy, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Typescripts (4), photograph, clippings.
  - Rauschenberg, Robert, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Typescript, photographs (18), publicity, clippings.
  - Realism. "The Art of Real", exhibit at Museum of Modern Art, 1968 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
  - Rebay, Hilla von, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
  - Reder, Bernard, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
  - Refregier, Anton, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescript, publicity, clipping.
  - Rembrandt, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (64), publicity, clippings.
  - Rembrandt and His Time. Traveling exhibition in the USA, 1967 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
  - Renoir, Pierre Auguste, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (42), publicity, clippings.
    See also Box 25, Folder 11.
  - Restoration and care of art works, Undated; typescript, brochure, clippings (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
  - Riemenschneider, Tilman. Exhibit in North Carolina, 1962 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
  - Rifesser, Joseph. Catalog of exhibit, 1965 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
    Typescripts (2), photograph, clippings.
  - Rivers, Larry, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
    Typescript, photograph, publicity, clippings.
  - Rodin, Auguste. Fakes of drawings, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
    Also late bronze castings. Typescripts (3), photographs (16), publicity, clippings.
  - Römischer Jahreszeiten Sarkophag: Roman Sarcophagus purchase by Metropolitan Museum, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    Typescript, photographs (4).
  - Roman Portraits. Exhibit Worcester, 1961 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
    Typescript, photographs (36), publicity.
  - Rothko, Mark, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Includes retrospective at the Guggenheim Museum, 1978/1979. Typescripts (8), photographs (24), publicity, correspondence.
  - Rothko, Mark, Undated; clippings (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
  - Rubens, Peter Paul, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - Russian Art. Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1977 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Sassetta Predella. Panels, Detroit Institute of Art, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    Typescript, photograph, publicity.
  - Schiele, Egon. Book review of the oeuvre catalogue by Otto Kallir, 1966 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
  - Schneider, Herbert. Exhibit in New York, 1976 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Including a signed collage (stored in vault). Typescript, catalog, clippings.
  - Schultze, Bernard and Ursula. Catalog, clippings, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Original artwork (Bernard [1], Gisela [1], signed and dedicated, stored in vault, 6-4-2).
  - Sculpture, Modern. Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, 1966-1967 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 25)
    Typescript, photographs (15).
  - Scythians, Art of the. Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1975 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 26)
    Typescript, photographs (4), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Sheeler, Charles. Some notes but no finished text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 27)
    Photographs (12), publicity, clippings.
  - Sisley, Alfred. Exhibit at Wildenstein, 1966 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 28)
    With illustrated catalog.
  - Smith, David. Exhibit at Guggenheim Museum, 1969 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 29)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (13), publicity, clippings.
  - Soutine, Chaim. Museum of Modern Art, 1950-1951 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 30)
  - Spanische Kunst: Spanish Art, Modern. Exhibits at Guggenheim Museum, Museum of Modern Art, Cintas Collection of Spanish Art in Brooklyn Museum, 1963 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 31)
    Typescript, photographs (51), publicity, clippings.
  - Springer, Ferdinand. Illustrated catalog, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 32)
  - Städte: "A Century of City Views". Smithsonian Institution traveling exhibit, 1957-1958 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 33)
    Typescript, photographs (27), publicity, clipping.
  - Steinberg, Saul. Exhibit at Whitney Museum, 1978 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 34)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Surrealism and Dadaism. Exhibits, 1968, 1977 (Box 7 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 35)
    Typescript, photographs (19), publicity, clippings.
  - Swiss Avant-garde. Exhibit in New York, 1971 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 1)
    Draft in pencil, but no finished text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Thera. Excavations on the Greek island, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 2)
    Typescripts (3), photograph, clippings, monograph.
  - Thracians, Art of the. Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1977 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 3)
    Typescript, photographs (8), publicity, clippings.
  - Tiere in der Kunst: Animals in Art, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 4)
    Typescript, publicity.
  - Tinguely, Jean, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 5)
  - Toulouse-Lautrec, Henri de, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (24), publicity, clippings.
  - Trompe l'Oeil in art and advertisement, ca. 1951 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 7)
    With numerous original photos by Fritz Neugass. Typescripts (4), photographs (59), correspondence, publicity, clippings.
  - Turku, Trajan. Posthumous exhibit of the sculptor, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 8)
    Typescript only, no photographs.
  - Turner, J. M. W. Exhibit at Museum of Modern Art, 1966 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 9)
  - Tut-ench-Amun: Tutankhamun. Exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1978-1979 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 10)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (22), publicity.
  - Tut-ench-Amun: Tutankhamun, Undated; clippings (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 11)
  - Uhde, Wilhelm. Memorial articles, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 12)
  - Utrillo, Maurice, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 13)
  - Van Dongen, Kees, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 14)
  - Van Eyck, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 15)
    January Purchases by the Museum in Detroit and by the Frick Collection. Typescripts (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Van Gogh, Vincent. Debate around the self-portrait in the Goetz collection, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 16)
  - Velasquez, Diego. "Juan de Pareja" purchase by the Metropolitan Museum, 1971 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 17)
    Typescript, photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Vermeer, Johannes, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 18)
    Including material of the 1966 exhibit in The Hague, "Het Licht van Vermeer".
    typescript, photographs (7), clippings.
  - Villon, Jacques, Marcel Duchamp, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 19)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (7), publicity, clippings.
  - Vuillard, Edouard, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 20)
  - Wandteppiche: Tapestries. 14th-16th centuries, Exhibit at the Metropolitan Museum, 1974 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 21)
    Including illustrated Museum Bulletin. Typescripts (2), photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - World's Fair, New York, Pavilion of Fine Arts, 1965 (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 22)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, including his son James Wyeth, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 23)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (31), publicity, clippings.
  - Zeitlose Kunst: Timeless Aspect of Modern Art, Undated (Box 8 (1-Art and Artists), Folder 24)
    Typescript, photographs (13).
- Museums & Private Collections, 1950s-1979; 2; 148 file folders
  This series consists of typescripts by Neugass, photographs and clippings on museums? permanent and temporary collections as well as collections of private individuals.
  - African Museum. Museum of African Art, Washington, opening 1964 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 25)
  - Aldrich, Larry. Exhibit at opening of Aldrich Museum, CT, 1964 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 26)
  - Amerikanische Sammler: American Collectors, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 27)
    Typescripts (6), notes, photographs (13), clippings.
  - Arensberg, Louise & Walter. Collection in Philadelphia, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 28)
  - Art of Antiquity. Private Collectors, Exhibit at Metropolitan Museum, 1959 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 29)
    Typescript, photographs (9), publicity, clippings.
  - Artmobile, Virginia Museum, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 30)
  - Asia Society. Bequest of John D. Rockefeller collection of Asiatic to the Society, 1974 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 31)
    No article by Fritz Neugass. Photograph, correspondence, publicity, clipping.
  - Avnet, Joan and Lester. Collection of modern drawings, exhibited at the Museum of Modern Art, 1978 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 32)
    Including catalog, some notes, no text by Fritz Neugass. Publicity, photographs (12), clipping.
  - Baker, Walter C. Collection of Drawings, exhibited at the Metropolitan Museum, 1960 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 33)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art. The Cone Collection, Dr. Claribel & Etta Cone, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 34)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (27), publicity, clippings.
  - Baltimore Museum of Art. "From El Greco to Pollock" exhibit, 1968 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 35)
    Typescript, photographs (14), publicity.
  - Baltimore, Walters Art Gallery. Including special issue of Apollo, 1966 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 36)
    Numerous notes by Fritz Neugass, but no finished article. Photographs (10), clippings.
  - Bareiss, Walter. Collection of Greek vases and modern drawings. Notes by Fritz Neugass, no finished article, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 37)
    Photographs (18), publicity, clippings.
  - Barnes, Albert C. Foundation, Merion, PA, Opening for the Public, 1961 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 38)